Guide to the Ron Whyte Papers
Beinecke Rare Book and Manuscript Library
Ron Whyte papers
1939-1995
YCAL MSS 670
Beinecke Rare Book and Manuscript Library
144.09
(171 boxes)
The papers consist of correspondence, writings, printed material, photographs, audiovisual material, and personal papers that document the life and work of playwright, editor, and activist Ron Whyte (circa 1942-1989). The largest series, Writings, includes drafts and circulating versions of dozens of works of drama and prose by Ron Whyte, including many unproduced plays. The documentation of Whyte's writings also includes material from his time as a student, spanning from high school to graduate study at the Yale School of Drama and the Union Theological Seminary. The papers also include a substantial quantity of audio recordings of dramatic works written or produced by Whyte. Other material, including subject files and unsorted papers, documents the varied and prolific career of Whyte, including his advocacy for people with disabilities.
Whyte, Ron
Immediate Source of Acquisition
Gift of Paul Bradley, 2004.
Conditions Governing Access
The materials are open for research.
Boxes 138-159: (reel-to-reel audiotapes): Restricted fragile material. Reference copies may be requested. Consult Access Services for further information.
Boxes 105, 111, 112, 115, 160-167 (record albums, audiocassettes, and videocassettes): Use of original is restricted. Reference copies may be requested. Consult Access services for further information.
Arrangement
Organized into ten series: I. Correspondence, 1939-1994. II. Writings, 1957-1995. III. Educational Papers, 1956-1984. IV. Professional Papers, 1962-1995. V. Subject Files, 1957-1989. VI. Personal Papers, 1950-1989. VII. Printed Material, 1939-1985. VIII. Photographs, 1953-1991. IX. Unsorted Papers, circa 1967-1990. X. Audiovisual Material, circa 1973-1980.
Ron Whyte
Ron Whyte (circa 1942-1989), American playwright and book review editor for the Soho Weekly News, was the author of the plays Welcome to Andromeda (1969) and Disability: A Comedy (1978), and the executive director of the National Task Force for Disability and the Arts, 1977-1980. Ron Whyte's year of birth is variously recorded as 1941 or 1942.
Scope and Contents
The papers consist of correspondence, writings, printed material, photographs, audiovisual material, and personal papers that document the life and work of playwright, editor, and activist Ron Whyte. The largest series, Writings, includes drafts and circulating versions of dozens of works of drama and prose by Ron Whyte, including many unproduced plays. The documentation of Whyte's writings also includes material from his time as a student, spanning from high school to graduate study at the Yale School of Drama and the Union Theological Seminary. The papers also include a substantial quantity of audio recordings of dramatic works written or produced by Whyte. Other material, including subject files and unsorted papers, documents the varied and prolific career of Whyte, including his advocacy for people with disabilities.
American literature -- 20th Century; Authors, American; Drama -- United States; Dramatists -- United States; People with disabilities -- United States; Audiovisual materials; Photographic prints; Authors -- United States -- 20th Century; Dramatists -- United States -- 20th Century; Whyte, Ron; Yale School of Drama; Union Theological Seminary (New York, N.Y.)
- Correspondence, 1939-1994; Series I; 11; (11 boxes)
  Arrangement
  Not arranged in any particular order.
  Scope and Contents
  Series I consists chiefly of incoming correspondence, though files occasionally include notes or drafts of outgoing correspondence. The files are unsorted and include both personal and professional correspondence with colleagues, family members, and organizations, relating to Ron Whyte's writing, the production of his dramatic works, and his work as an activist; to broader cultural and literary events and topics, especially as they relate to the New York City area; and to personal, financial, and medical issues.
  - Unsorted correspondence, 1958-1992, undated; 18 (Box 1)
  - Unsorted correspondence, 1965-1989, undated; 14 (Box 2)
  - Unsorted correspondence, 1950-1989, undated; 12 (Box 3)
  - Unsorted correspondence, 1968-1986, undated; 17 (Box 4)
  - Unsorted correspondence, 1963-1990, undated; 15 (Box 5)
  - Unsorted correspondence, 1964-1991, undated; 16 (Box 6)
  - Unsorted correspondence, 1957-1989, undated; 18 (Box 7)
  - Unsorted correspondence, 1939-1992, undated; 21 (Box 8)
  - Unsorted correspondence, 1967-1989, undated; 24 (Box 9)
  - Unsorted correspondence, 1950-1988, undated; 22 (Box 10)
  - Unsorted correspondence, 1973-1994, undated; 35 (Box 11)
- Writings, 1957-1995; Series II; 72; (72 boxes)
  Organized into two subseries: Writings of Ron Whyte, and Writings of Others.
  Series II consists chiefly of drafts of writings, most typescript, some corrected. Some files also include notes and other related material. Writings of Ron Whyte are chiefly dramatic works, but also include reviews and other works of prose. Notes and Notebooks include drafts of unidentified writings, lectures, and notes relating to various writing and editing projects. Writings of Others appear to consist of material that was sent to Ron Whyte for his review or editorial input, and versions of dramatic works produced by Ron Whyte.
  - Writings of Ron Whyte
    Organized under three headings: Major Works of Drama and Prose, Notes and Notebooks, and Reviews.
    - Major Works of Drama and Prose
      Arranged alphabetically by title. Untitled and unsorted works are filed at the end.
      - Act Two, 1980 May 4, undated; 4 (Box 12)
      - Ah-Thuk and the Princess of Onan-Du, undated (Box 12)
      - Alas, Poor Yetta, undated (Box 12)
      - Amerikan Schrapnel, undated (Box 12)
      - Anatomy of a Controversy, undated; 2 (Box 12)
      - Andromeda II, 1979-1980, undated; 14 (Box 12)
      - Andromeda II, 1980-1982, undated; 6 (Box 13)
      - Andromeda III, 1980, undated; 2 (Box 13)
      - Ann Richards, 1988, undated; 5 (Box 13)
      - Arise and Sleep!, undated (Box 13)
      - Ask Me No Questions!, 1967; 3 (Box 13)
      - Banned Books for Sale, undated (Box 13)
      - Bertolucci, Incest, the Critics and Nathaniel Hawthorne, undated (Box 13)
      - Biology Lab #25, undated (Box 13)
      - Birth of a Genre -- Death of a Literature?, 1978; 2 (Box 13)
      - Black is a Beautiful Color, 1968 (Box 13)
      - My Black Notebooks, 1993 (Box 13)
      - Black Snow, Red Rain, 1968; 2 (Box 13)
      - A Book I Thought Up, 1968, undated; 3 (Box 14)
      - Breaking Point, 1963 August 29 (Box 14)
      - Briefing On Off-Broadway Theater: 1957-1977, 3 (Box 14)
      - The Butterfly Beast, 1970, undated; 4 (Box 14)
      - Caliban's Mother, 1968 (Box 14)
      - Carmen Miranda, undated (Box 14)
      - Carte de Visite, undated; 3 (Box 14)
      - A Case of a Saint, undated (Box 14)
      - Cassettes, 1971 (Box 14)
      - A Cast Away, 1976-1977, undated; 8 (Box 14)
      - Catch a Tiger in the Bronx!, undated (Box 14)
      - The Charles La Rue Show, 1971 (Box 15)
      - The Children, undated; 5 (Box 15)
      - Children of Imagination Night, undated; 2 (Box 15)
      - Choruses for the Van Camp Report, undated (Box 15)
      - Code Name Martha, undated (Box 15)
      - Command Performance, 1977; 2 (Box 15)
      - The Comic-Book World, undated (Box 15)
      - Contacts with the Underworld, 1969; 2 (Box 15)
      - Cooper Union, undated (Box 15)
      - Counter-Cultures, 1979-1981, undated; 4 (Box 15)
      - Counter-Cultures, 1967-1979, undated; 4 (Box 16)
      - The Cruise of Abdc and His Associates During Pre-Recorded History, undated (Box 16)
      - David, 1968; 18 (Box 16)
      - Death, undated (Box 16)
      - Death Be Not Pushy or Black Borscht, undated; 2 (Box 16)
      - Death Be Not Pushy or Black Borscht (continued), undated; 3 (Box 17)
      - The Death of Fanny Hill, undated (Box 17)
      - The Death of Lizzie Borden, 1967 (Box 17)
      - The Death of Mother's Man or Santa Claus, the Avenger, 1964, undated; 2 (Box 17)
      - Deformity, 1981, undated; 2 (Box 17)
      - The Devil's Book, 1969 (Box 17)
      - Dialogue for Voices and Shotgun, 1986, undated; 2 (Box 17)
      - Diary of David Jensen, 1968 (Box 17)
      - Dime, 1970, undated; 8 (Box 17)
      - Dinosaurs, 1968, undated; 2 (Box 17)
      - Dinosaurs, 1979, undated; 2 (Box 18)
      - Disability, 1978-1984, undated; 21 (Box 18)
      - Disability, 1978-1980, undated; 22 (Box 19)
      - Disability, 1978-1995, undated; 22 (Box 20)
      - Disability, 1979-1983, undated; 20 (Box 21)
      - Distant Signals, 1985, undated; 6 (Box 22)
      - Dorothy & Elizabeth, undated; 4 (Box 22)
      - Down by the Shalimar, 1970, undated; 2 (Box 22)
      - Dreamers, 1987, undated; 8 (Box 22)
      - The Dream of Love, undated (Box 22)
      - Dr. Strange, undated (Box 23)
      - Earth Catalogue, undated (Box 23)
      - "E--C--E" or "Everyman -- Cripple -- Everyman", 1973; 3 (Box 23)
      - Emil and Nell, 1967-1977, undated; 14 (Box 23)
      - Emil and Nell, 1967-1983, undated; 17 (Box 24)
      - Emil and Nell, 1967-1989, undated; 18 (Box 25)
      - Emil and Nell, 1975, undated; 5 (Box 26)
      - Everyone's Art, undated (Box 26)
      - Exeunt Dying, undated; 2 (Box 26)
      - Experiments in Collaborative Theatre, undated (Box 26)
      - Excuse of a Funeral, 1969 (Box 26)
      - The Extinction of Alexander Pope, 1971-[1979], undated; 14 (Box 26)
      - "F", 1969, undated; 2 (Box 26)
      - "F", 1969; 2 (Box 27)
      - Faraway Look, undated (Box 27)
      - A Few Words for an Air-Shaft, undated (Box 27)
      - The Fido Girls Attack School or The Brigands of Putemen Hallway, undated (Box 27)
      - A Film About the College Scene, undated (Box 27)
      - Flowers for You, 1967; 16 (Box 27)
      - The Flower that Wouldn't Grow, undated (Box 27)
      - Food, undated (Box 27)
      - Francois, 1972, undated; 6 (Box 27)
      - Francois, 1974; 5 (Box 28)
      - Funeral March for a One-Man Band, 1968-1978, undated; 20 (Box 28)
      - Funeral March for a One-Man Band, 1967-1990, undated; 17 (Box 29)
      - Funeral March for a One-Man Band, 1967-1978, undated; 19 (Box 30)
      - Funeral March for a One-Man Band, 1967-1970, undated; 20 (Box 31)
      - Funeral March for a One-Man Band, 1967-1970, undated; 17 (Box 32)
      - Funeral March for a One-Man Band, 1976-1979, undated; 16 (Box 33)
      - Gadzooks!, 1965, undated; 10 (Box 33)
      - Gadzooks!, 1965, undated; 3 (Box 34)
      - The Girl Who Ate New York City, undated (Box 34)
      - Girl with Lute, 1964-1965, undated; 6 (Box 34)
      - Glass Hands, undated (Box 34)
      - Goddesses, 1988; 2 (Box 34)
      - Going to Lilly Whites' Party with Sgt. Pepper, 1969 (Box 34)
      - The Grace of the Handicapped, 1977; 5 (Box 34)
      - Graffiti, undated; 2 (Box 34)
      - Gray Matters, 1977, undated; 3 (Box 34)
      - Green Nuns in Summer, undated (Box 34)
      - Gubec-Beg, 1975 July 30 (Box 34)
      - Hammet's Child, undated; 3 (Box 34)
      - Hansel & Gretel, undated (Box 35)
      - The Happiness Button, 1971, undated; 8 (Box 35)
      - Happiness Cage, undated; 8 (Box 35)
      - Happy Trails and the Four--H Spread, undated; 3 (Box 35)
      - Haven, 1970; 8 (Box 36)
      - Hay, What?, undated (Box 36)
      - Hell Hath No Fury, undated (Box 36)
      - "H H H: Howard", 1987; 4 (Box 36)
      - Help, Mother, I'm Murthered!, undated (Box 36)
      - Hoo Rah for Everything, 1964 (Box 36)
      - Horatio, 1970-1975, undated; 6 (Box 36)
      - Horatio, 1969-1974, undated; 20 (Box 37)
      - Horatio, 1967, undated; 24 (Box 38)
      - Hudson River Anthology, undated (Box 38)
      - Humane Interest, 1969-1979, undated; 3 (Box 38)
      - Humane Interest, 1979, undated; 6 (Box 39)
      - The Hunchback of Notre-Dame, 1981, undated; 9 (Box 39)
      - The Hunchback of Notre-Dame, 1980, undated; 22 (Box 40)
      - The Hunchback of Notre-Dame, 1979-1981, undated; 18 (Box 41)
      - The Hunchback of Notre-Dame, undated; 4 (Box 42)
      - The Imaginary Invalid, undated; 4 (Box 42)
      - The Incredible "Captain Clef" or "Beware, Puny Mortals!", 1968; 2 (Box 42)
      - In Print, undated (Box 42)
      - Inquisitions, 1984, undated; 2 (Box 42)
      - Invocation for Nine Voices, undated; 3 (Box 42)
      - Isis. Osiris, undated (Box 42)
      - The Jessica Trespass, 1988 (Box 42)
      - The Joggers, undated (Box 42)
      - Jonathan, undated; 4 (Box 42)
      - Journal: C. E. j 393, undated (Box 42)
      - Kampus Kapers, 1963-1964; 4 (Box 42)
      - The Kenneth Book, 1968 September (Box 43)
      - The King's Head, undated; 3 (Box 43)
      - Ladies of the Canyon, undated; 2 (Box 43)
      - Lady Samantha, undated; 5 (Box 43)
      - The Last Day of Oscar Wilde, undated; 4 (Box 43)
      - The Last of the Self-Made Men, 1969-1976, undated; 5 (Box 43)
      - Last Messages, 1967 (Box 43)
      - Life Deformed: An Approach to the Politics of Disability, 1976 (Box 43)
      - Life-Songs, 1978-1979; 3 (Box 43)
      - Little Illustrated Books for Little Illustrated People, undated (Box 43)
      - Live from Jackson Heights, undated (Box 43)
      - The Look, undated; 3 (Box 43)
      - The Look, undated; 2 (Box 44)
      - Love / Death on West 99th Street, 1979 (Box 44)
      - Love is the Crooked Thing, 1985; 5 (Box 44)
      - Lullabye Antonia, 1987 (Box 44)
      - Magic and Madison Avenue, 1968 (Box 44)
      - Malevolence Unlimited, or "Snarks Remarks", undated (Box 44)
      - A Man and his Wife at Breakfast, undated (Box 44)
      - Marvel Comics: The Untold Story, undated; 6 (Box 44)
      - Materials Gathered Toward an Evening of New-Cabaret at the Actors Studio, 1979 (Box 44)
      - Marvin's Garden, undated (Box 44)
      - Meep, Gibber, Treason and Plot, 1968; 2 (Box 45)
      - Method Man, undated; 2 (Box 45)
      - Miltown: The Indignant Centipede, undated (Box 45)
      - The Mind Snatchers, undated; 2 (Box 45)
      - Minorities in Film, undated (Box 45)
      - Minor Poems: Volume One, 1970 (Box 45)
      - Montana 8/78: Disability Consciousness-Raising: Day-by-Day Script, 1978; 3 (Box 45)
      - Mother and Child, 1965-1987, undated; 13 (Box 45)
      - Mother's Day, undated; 2 (Box 45)
      - Mr. Georg McFillow, undated (Box 45)
      - Mrs. L. G. Charlotte's Silent Movie, 1972 (Box 45)
      - My Aunt Metta, 1969 (Box 46)
      - My Dinosaur, 1968-1970, undated; 4 (Box 46)
      - The Mystery Woman Behind Raggedy Ann, undated (Box 46)
      - Naked Man, undated (Box 46)
      - The National Enquirer, undated; 3 (Box 46)
      - Neil Simon Sunday, undated (Box 46)
      - Nest-House, undated (Box 46)
      - New Arts for New People, undated (Box 46)
      - The New Haven Cycle, undated (Box 46)
      - The New Juliet, undated (Box 46)
      - Nero-Hero, undated (Box 46)
      - The Normals, 1964, undated; 2 (Box 46)
      - Notes from an Underworld, 1985 (Box 46)
      - Old Women Don't Swing, undated (Box 46)
      - A Page from the Devil's Book, undated; 6 (Box 46)
      - Parable of the Mustard Seeds, undated; 3 (Box 46)
      - Paradise Received, undated (Box 46)
      - The Parents, 1978, undated; 8 (Box 47)
      - Passin' Thru', undated; 3 (Box 47)
      - Peppermints, undated (Box 47)
      - Pig. Horse. Dragonfly, undated; 4 (Box 47)
      - Piquant, undated; 2 (Box 47)
      - Places, undated (Box 47)
      - A Play, undated (Box 47)
      - Playboy Story, 1969 October (Box 47)
      - Plays, Films, Mime, Revues, 1965, undated; 4 (Box 47)
      - The Poe Project, 1978; 3 (Box 47)
      - Point of Vector, 1989 (Box 48)
      - Point Zero, undated; 2 (Box 48)
      - A Portrait of the Artist as a Young Cripple, 1971-1979, undated; 20 (Box 48)
      - Postcards from the Outside World, 1965 (Box 49)
      - Pot-Boiler, 1968 (Box 49)
      - The Powers that Bloom in the Spring, 1969; 5 (Box 49)
      - Prime Time Paranoia, undated (Box 49)
      - Prologue: Truth Will Out, undated (Box 49)
      - The Psychic Shape of the Crash to the Bash, undated (Box 49)
      - Punch and Judas, 1970; 16 (Box 49)
      - Punch and Judas, 1970, undated; 6 (Box 50)
      - Quasimodo's Wedding, 1979, undated; 9 (Box 50)
      - The Radio City Music Hall Book, undated (Box 50)
      - Ragnarok, or the Education of Cris, undated; 4 (Box 51)
      - Raps from the Big Apple, undated (Box 51)
      - Rattle of Small Bones, 1969 (Box 51)
      - Rattle of Small Skeletons, 1969; 2 (Box 51)
      - Ravenous Grave, 1978, undated; 12 (Box 51)
      - Ravenous Grave, 1978, undated; 13 (Box 52)
      - Resurrection: Born Again, 1988; 2 (Box 52)
      - Revelations or the Healing of Chris, 1980, undated; 5 (Box 52)
      - Revelations or the Healing of Chris, 1980, undated; 7 (Box 53)
      - The Revolt, 1969, undated; 10 (Box 53)
      - Rock Lyrics, 1970 (Box 53)
      - The Rounds, 1969, undated; 10 (Box 53)
      - Run Away Sex?, undated (Box 53)
      - Salt of the Earth, undated (Box 54)
      - Santa Claus, the Avenger, 1965, undated; 2 (Box 54)
      - Scary Mona, 1968 (Box 54)
      - Science Fiction: Etc., undated (Box 54)
      - A Season in Hell, 1969 (Box 54)
      - A Season on Earth, 1970, undated; 9 (Box 54)
      - See the Movie, Read the Trash, undated (Box 54)
      - Sermonettes, undated; 8 (Box 54)
      - The Seven Day Weekend, 1967-1970, undated; 9 (Box 55)
      - Sex and Death, 1974, undated; 4 (Box 55)
      - A Sherlockian Christmas Carol, undated (Box 55)
      - The Sidelong Glances of a Pigeon Kicker, undated; 7 (Box 55)
      - The Sidelong Glances of a Pigeon Kicker, undated; 4 (Box 56)
      - Sing Out, Louise!, 1966 (Box 56)
      - The Six Who Travelled the World, undated (Box 56)
      - The Size of Summer, 1969 January-March; 4 (Box 56)
      - Sleeping Beauty, undated (Box 56)
      - Skin Flick, 1970; 5 (Box 56)
      - Skinnydippin' With the Muse, undated (Box 56)
      - Snow Filth, 1965-1967; 7 (Box 56)
      - Something of Envy: Something of Love, undated (Box 57)
      - Sourcebook of American Theatrical History, undated (Box 57)
      - Spoon River Revisited, undated (Box 57)
      - Spring in the East Village, undated (Box 57)
      - Spring's Awakening, undated; 2 (Box 57)
      - Star Trek Valentine, undated (Box 57)
      - State!, 1963 (Box 57)
      - The State of Grace, undated; 4 (Box 57)
      - The Stitch-Gypsy, 1968 (Box 57)
      - A Story of the Enf of the Dark Ages, undated (Box 57)
      - The Story of Film, 1976; 7 (Box 57)
      - Sub-Mariner, undated (Box 57)
      - Suffer Little Children, undated; 2 (Box 57)
      - Summer Mementos of West 99th Street, undated (Box 57)
      - Summer Mementos of West 99th Street, undated (Box 58)
      - Super-Kosmik-Kripple-Skreenplayriter-Komix, 1970-1976; 2 (Box 58)
      - Thalidomide #1104, 1967; 2 (Box 58)
      - "That's Why We Came to Yale", undated (Box 58)
      - Theater and Film, undated (Box 58)
      - Theater and the Contemporary Worship Service, undated; 2 (Box 58)
      - Those Capable, undated (Box 58)
      - Tit-Flick, undated (Box 58)
      - Tom Jefferson Still Lives?, 1970, undated; 6 (Box 58)
      - Tom Sawyer - Tiny Tim, 1978 (Box 58)
      - Tom Swift, 1965 October 19, undated; 8 (Box 58)
      - Triage, undated; 2 (Box 58)
      - The True Account of an American Experiment 1863-?, undated (Box 59)
      - Two Gun Kid, undated (Box 59)
      - Two of Us, undated (Box 59)
      - Ubu Rex, undated; 7 (Box 59)
      - Ulysses Aged, undated (Box 59)
      - Under the Covers, undated; 3 (Box 59)
      - Unfinished Fiction, undated (Box 59)
      - The Universe Loves to Create, undated (Box 59)
      - Untitled Dan "From the New World", 1982; 2 (Box 59)
      - Up Against It, undated (Box 59)
      - Up for Grabs, 1972 (Box 59)
      - Valentine's Eve, 1967 (Box 59)
      - Variety Obit, 1969, undated; 8 (Box 59)
      - Variety Obit, 1969, undated; 2 (Box 60)
      - A Very Good Year, undated (Box 60)
      - The Vietnam War Movie, undated (Box 60)
      - Virga Vay and Allen Cedar, undated; 3 (Box 60)
      - Voice, 1987 (Box 60)
      - Waltz Triage, 1988 (Box 60)
      - Wed and Die, undated (Box 60)
      - Welcome to Andromeda, 1967-1968, undated; 17 (Box 60)
      - Welcome to Andromeda, 1968-1979, undated; 24 (Box 61)
      - What is Playwriting?, 1981 November 7 (Box 61)
      - Without, 1967 (Box 61)
      - Why Do Elephants Wear Green Sneakers?, 1969, undated; 10 (Box 62)
      - Wouldn't You Like to Know?, undated; 3 (Box 62)
      - Wrong Turn on the Yellow Brick Road, 1965; 9 (Box 62)
      - Yankee Doodle Boy, undated (Box 62)
      - Yankee Doodle Boy, 1970, undated; 15 (Box 63)
      - Yankee Doodle Boy, 1978, undated; 5 (Box 64)
      - You Tell Me Yours, 1970; 2 (Box 64)
      - Zoroaster, 1960 February 15 (Box 64)
      - Early writings, 1957-1960, undated; 10 (Box 64)
      - Fabiano Canosa: projects, 1975; 2 (Box 64)
      - Fiction: Fragments, undated (Box 64)
      - Lyrics, 1968-1969, undated; 6 (Box 64)
      - Page from Guitar Player Magazine with music scores of "Beginnings: An Unreleased Jimi Hendrix Solo", 1972 September (Box 64)
        Transcribed and annotated by Lee Ritenour. Includes 7" flexi phonodisc recording of the song.
      - Music scores, undated; 9 (Box 65)
      - Poems, undated; 3 (Box 65)
      - Unsorted writings, undated; 17 (Box 65)
      - Unsorted writings, undated; 2 (Box 66)
      - Unsorted writings, undated; 17 (Box 67)
      - Unsorted writings, undated; 26 (Box 68)
      - Unsorted writings, undated; 25 (Box 69)
      - Unsorted writings, undated; 21 (Box 70)
      - Unsorted writings, undated; 23 (Box 71)
      - Unsorted writings, undated; 20 (Box 72)
      - Unsorted writings, undated; 20 (Box 73)
      - Unsorted writings, undated; 18 (Box 74)
    - Notes and Notebooks
      - Notes and notebooks, undated; 16 (Box 75)
      - Notes and notebooks, undated; 13 (Box 76)
      - Notes and notebooks, undated; 22 (Box 77)
    - Reviews
      - Book reviews, circa 1973 - 1980; 3 (Box 78)
  - Writings of Others
    Arranged alphabetically by author. Reviews of Ron Whyte's work are filed at the end.
    - Andre, Michael. How I Blew Up the World, undated (Box 78)
    - Barclay, William. A Life of Christ, 1977 (Box 78)
    - Barry, Julian. Take That!, 1968 (Box 78)
    - Benjamin, Lee and Leyden, James. Rough 'N' Ready, undated (Box 78)
    - Benjamin, Lee and Leyden, James. Bayou Flute, undated (Box 78)
    - Benjamin, Lee and Leyden, James. Shillelagh-O, undated (Box 78)
    - Berger, Ted. The Shoemakers' Holiday, 1964 (Box 78)
    - Bono, Steve. Untitled, undated (Box 78)
    - Bradley, Kathryn C. Brown Oakland, undated; 2 (Box 78)
    - Bradley, William L. Siam Then, 1976-1981, undated; 8 (Box 78)
    - Bradley, William L. Siam Then, circa 1972-1981; 13 (Box 79)
    - Brecht, Bertolt. To Those Who Are Young, undated (Box 79)
    - Brown, Michael. Different Times, 1972 (Box 79)
    - Chew, Birdell. The Time of the Blue Jay, 1968 (Box 79)
    - Cristofer, Michael. From the City of Hope, undated (Box 79)
    - Davidson, David. Gideon's Trumpet, 1965 July 12 (Box 79)
    - Feingold, Michael. Faustine, 1981 October (Box 79)
    - Gershe, Leonard. Butterflies are Free, undated (Box 79)
    - Gianfriddo, Thomas G. Poems and Things, 1961 October 31 (Box 79)
    - Gray, Natasha. The Death-Mask of Oscar Wilde, undated (Box 80)
    - Groddeck, Georg. The World of Man, undated (Box 80)
    - Hugo, Victor. Notre-Dame de Paris, undated; 2 (Box 80)
    - Jessup, Richard. Monty Nash, undated (Box 80)
    - Joseph, James A. Profiles in Philanthropy, undated (Box 80)
    - Katkov, Norman. Ben Casey, 1962 October 18 (Box 80)
    - Koslow, Michael. Man & What?, undated (Box 80)
    - Koslow, Michael. Lips, undated (Box 80)